Carl Collins

PROFILE

A confident individual with 15 years of experience in insurance sales and a track record of new business acquisition. Bachelor's degree in business administration from the University of California. Seven years of experience in a sales management position with proven performance of excellent performance and ability to motivate a team. Strong aptitude for leadership and a results-oriented approach to work.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Insurance Sales Manager

The Insurance Company, San Diego, CA | June 2014 - February 2021

- Marketed new products to both new and existing clients with a 65% sale rate
- ♦ Experience in quoting insurance rates
- Prepared and delivered clear and effective sales scripts
- Compiled and maintained marketing status reports and client contact lists

Insurance Sales Specialist

Insurance and Sales Corporation, San Diego, CA | March 2006 - May 2014

- Created proposals in order to generate new customer leads
- Attended networking events and trade shows
- Fielded all inbound and outbound calls and emails
- Followed up all sales inquiries with a 72% uptake rate

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Financial Engineering

The University of California, Berkeley, CA, September 2002 -September 2005

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

The University of California, Berkeley, CA, September 1999 -July 2002

KEY SKILLS

- Gathered accurate marketplace intelligence to increase sales
- Friendly and professional customer service manner
- Responsible for data entry via company software systems
- Contacted and liaised with underwriters

CERTIFICATIONS

- Chartered Property
 Casualty Underwriter
 Certificate in General Insurance, 2006
 (#14-00098)
- The American Institute for Chartered Property Casualty Underwriter Certificate, 2006 (#A45-7689090)